Downloaded @ subs4free.club
"Here" by David Byrne playing
Here is a region
Of abundant details
That is seldom used
And here is a region
That continues living
Even when the other
Sections are removed
Put your hand
out of your pocket
Wipe the sweat
off of your brow
Now it feels like
a bad connection
No more
information now
As it passes
through your neurons
Like a whisper in the dark
Raise your eyes
to one who loves you
It is safe
right where you are
Here is an area
Of great confusion
Here is a section
That's extremely precise
And here is an area
That needs attention
Here's the connection
To the opposite side
Here, too many sounds
For your brain
to comprehend
Here the sound
gets organized
Into things
that make some sense
Here there is something
We call hallucination
Is it the truth
Or merely
a description?
Here
Thank you.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you for...
Thank you for leaving your homes.
My name's David Byrne.
Thank you.
I can't take any credit for that.
I had no choice in the matter.
I read something,
well, kinda surprising
and amazing the other day.
I read that babies' brains
have hundreds of millions
more neural connections
than we do as adults,
and that as we grow up,
we lose these connections.
So I wondered to myself,
what does this mean?
Does this mean that babies
are smarter than we are
and that as we grow up,
we get stupider and stupider
until we reach a...
a plateau of stupidity?
Which is where most of us are now.
Well...
What happens is...
we keep the connections
that are useful to us,
and, yes, there's a process
of pruning and elimination,
and we get rid of a lot of the others
until the ones that are left
define who we are as a person,
who we are as people.
They define how we perceive the world,
and the world appears
to make some kinda sense to us.
And maybe round about that time
we start asking ourselves
various questions
like, "Who am I?
"What do I want?
"How do I work this?
"What are those people
doing over there?
"Should I be doing that?
"Are they looking at me?
"Are they like me?
"Should I go over and talk to them?
Huh, maybe not. "
Try to figure this out,
wondering if there's,
you know, wondering if
there's a logic to it
and wondering if it's supposed
to make some kinda sense.
"I Know Sometimes
a Man Is Wrong" playing
I know sometimes
a man is wrong
I do believe
I know sometimes
a man is wrong
I'll be wrong
Until you're
next to me
I know sometimes
The world is wrong
I do believe
I know sometimes
The world is wrong
They'll be wrong
Until you're next to me
"Don't Worry About
the Government" playing
I see the clouds
that move across the sky
I see the wind
that moves the clouds away
It moves the clouds
over by the building
I pick the building
that I want to live in
I smell the pine trees
and the peaches in the woods
I see the pine cones
that fall by the highway
That's the highway
that goes to the building
That's the building
that I want to live in
It's over there
My building
has every convenience
It's gonna make
life easy for me
It's gonna be easy
to get things done
I will relax alone
with my loved ones
Loved ones, loved ones
Visit the building
Take the highway, park
And come up
and see me
I'll be working, working
But if you come visit
I'll put down
what I'm doing
My friends
are important
Don't you worry
'bout me
I wouldn't worry
about me
Don't you worry 'bout me
Don't you worry
'bout me
I see the states
across this big nation
I see the laws made
in Washington, D.C.
I think of the ones
I consider my favorites
I think of the people
that are working for me
Some civil servants are
just like my loved ones
They work so hard,
and they try to be strong
I'm a lucky guy
to live in my building
They own these buildings
to help them along
It's over there
My building
has every convenience
It's gonna make
life easy for me
It's gonna be easy
to get things done
I will relax along
with my loved ones
Loved ones, loved ones
Visit the building
Take the highway, park
And come up and see me
I'll be working, working
But if you come visit
I'll put down
what I'm doing
My friends
are important
Don't you worry 'bout me
I wouldn't
worry about me
Don't you worry 'bout me
Don't you worry 'bout
Me
"Lazy" playing
I'm
Wicked and I'm lazy
Oh-oh, don't you
wanna save me?
I'm lazy
when I'm lovin'
I'm lazy when I play
I'm lazy with my girlfriend
1,000 times a day
I'm lazy
when I'm speaking
I'm lazy when I talk
I'm lazy when I'm dancin'
And I'm lazy when I walk
I open up my mouth
Air comes rushing out
Nothing doing,
nada, never
How you
like me now?
Wouldn't it be mad?
Wouldn't it be fine?
Lazy, lucky lady dancin',
loving all the time?
Oh, I'm wicked and I'm lazy
Oh-oh, don't you
wanna save me?
Imagine there's
a girlfriend
Imagine there's a job
Imagine there's an answer
Imagine there's a God
Imagine I'm a devil
Imagine I'm a saint
Lazy money, lazy sexy,
lazy outta space
No tears are falling
from my eyes
I'm keeping
all the pain inside
Now, don't you wanna
live with me?
I'm lazy
as a man can be
Oh, I'm wicked and I'm lazy
Oh-oh, don't you wanna
save me?
Lazy when I work,
lazy all the day
Screaming all you like
But it only fades away
I'm lazy when I'm praying
Lazy on the job
Got a lazy mind,
a lazy eye
A lazy, lazy father
Hard men
Hard lives
Hard keeping it all inside
Good times
Good God
So lazy I almost stop
Oh, I'm wicked
and I'm lazy
Oh-oh, don't you
wanna save me?
Oh, I'm wicked
and I'm lazy
Oh-oh, don't you
wanna save me?
Thank you.
You know,
meeting people is hard,
but I know...
I know we have to do it.
These people over here,
they all met through apps.
Totally working for them.
These people over here...
don't need apps.
They're just supremely confident.
Well, some of 'em might be bluffing.
Some of 'em might be putting up a front
but that doesn't matter
'cause it's all working for them.
Meanwhile I'm...
Well, you know, observing,
trying to figure this out.
Objectively...
objectively I could never
figure out why,
why looking at a person
should be any more interesting
than looking at any other thing,
like, say, a bicycle
or a beautiful sunset
or, mm, nice bag of potato chips.
But, yeah, looking at people?
That's the best.
"This Must Be the Place" playing
Home is where I want to be
Pick me up
and turn me round
I feel numb
Born with a weak heart
Guess I must be
having fun
The less we say
about it the better
Make it up
as we go along
Feet on the ground
Head in the sky
It's okay
I know nothing's wrong
Nothing
Hi yo
I got plenty of time
You got light in your eyes
And you're standing here
beside me
I love the passing of time
Never for money
Always for love
Cover up and say good night
Say good night
Home is where
I want to be
But I guess
I'm already there
I come home
She lifted up her wings
I guess that this
must be the place
I can't tell
one from another
Did I find you
or you find me?
There was a time
before we were born
If someone asks,
this is where I'll be
Where I'll be
Hi yo
We drift in and out
Sing into my mouth
Out of all those
kinds of people
You got a face
with a view
I'm just an animal
looking for a home
And share the same space
for a minute or two
And you love me
till my heart stops
Love me till I'm dead
Eyes that light up
Eyes look through you
Cover up the blank spots
Hit me on the head
I got...
Ah, ooh
Ooh, ooh, ooh
Thank you!
Thank you.
There's more.
My friend Brian Eno
suggested that we use
a nonsense poem by a Dada artist
as the lyrics for this next song,
which we did.
I was familiar with
a different Dada artist
who also wrote nonsense poetry.
His name was Kurt Schwitters,
and he recorded one of these in 1932.
It was called the "Ursonate,"
the primeval sonate.
Schwitters and some
of the others in the...
this group were, well...
they were using nonsense to make sense
of a world that didn't make sense.
To help explain a little bit
what that means,
here's a little bit
of the "Ursonate. "
It goes on like that for 40 minutes.
It'd be a different kinda movie.
The world they were trying
to make sense of, it...
Yes, it was pretty crazy.
Uh, there had recently
been an economic crash.
Uh, the Nazis were coming to power.
This is 1932,
and quite a few of
the countries they lived in
were sliding into fascism.
The Dada artist Hugo Ball
said that their artistic aims
were to remind the world
that there are people
of different, independent minds
beyond war and nationalism
who live for different ideals.
Hugo Ball wrote the words
to this next song.
"I Zimbra" playing
Gadji beri bimba clandridi
Lauli lonni cadori gadjam
A Bim beri glassala
glandride glassala
Tuffm, I zimbra
Bim blassa
galassasa zimbrabim
Blassa glallassasa
zimbrabim
A bim beri glassala
grandrid e glassala
Tuffm, I zimbra
Gadji beri bimba glandridi
Lauli lonni cadori gadjam
A bim beri
glassala glandrid
E glassala tuffm
I zimbra
Whoo!
"Slippery People" playing
What about the time?
You were rollin' over
Fall on your face
You must be having fun
Walk lightly
Think of a time
You'd best believe
that this thing is real
Now put away that gun
This part is simple
Try to recognize
what is in your mind
God help us,
help us lose our minds
These slippery people,
help us understand
What's the matter
with him?
He's all right
- How do you know?
- The Lord won't mind
- Don't know no games
- He's all right
Love from the bottom
to the top
- Turn like a wheel
- He's all right
See for yourself
The Lord won't mind
- We're gonna move
- Right now
Turn like a wheel
inside a wheel
I remember when
Sitting in the tub
Pulled out the plug
The water was running out
Cool down
Stop acting crazy
They're gonna leave
And we'll be
on our own now
Seven times five
They were living creatures
Watch 'em come to life
Right before your eyes
Backsliding
How do you do?
These slippery people
Gonna see you through
- What's the matter with him?
- He's all right
- How do you know?
- The Lord won't mind
- Don't know no games
- He's all right
Love from the bottom
to the top
- Turn like a wheel
- He's all right
- See for yourself
- The Lord won't mind
- We're gonna move
- Right now
- Turn like a wheel
- Inside a wheel
Bi, b-b-bi, b-bi, b-bi
B- b-bi, b-b-bi, bi-bi b-bi
Bi, bi, bi, bi,
bi, bi, bi
B- b-bi, b-b-bi,
b- bi, bi, b-bi
Bi, b-b-bi, b-bi, b-bi
B- b-bi, bi, bi, bi, bi, bi,
bi, bi, bi, bi, b-bi
Bi, b-b-bi, bi, b-b-bi
Bi, bi, bi, bi, bi,
bi, bi, bi, bi, bi
What's the matter
with him?
- He's all right
- How do you know?
- The Lord won't mind
- Don't know no games
- He's all right
- And we're going to the top
- Turn like a wheel
- He's all right
- See for yourself
- The Lord won't mind
- We're gonna move
- Right now
Turn like a wheel
inside a wheel
What's the matter
with him?
- He's all right
- How do you know?
The Lord won't mind
- Don't know no games
- He's all right
Love from the bottom
to the top
- Turn like a wheel
- He's all right
- See for yourself
- The Lord won't mind
- We're gonna move
- Right now
Turn like a wheel
inside a wheel
It's all right
The Lord won't mind
Love from the bottom
to the top
It's all right
The Lord won't mind
Right now
Turn like a wheel
inside a wheel
Thank you!
Whoo!
Thank you.
In 1976, the band I was in,
Talking Heads, got...
we got a record contract.
Okay...
Thank you. It was a contract
but not for very much money.
I spent some of my money
on a Sony Trinitron color television.
The screen was about that big,
but it was, it was
state-of-the-art in those days.
I must have still been a little bit,
a little bit isolated,
still trying to figure things out,
and I had an idea
that to help with that,
I should watch more TV.
Okay, I saw the TV
as being a kind of window,
and I would see the hopes and dreams
and aspirations and foibles
of my fellow Americans,
and I might learn something
about myself as well,
and maybe,
maybe I'd get some answers
to those questions
that I was asking myself earlier.
And I wondered to myself,
did the TV contain those
millions of lost connections
between me and them
and them and me?
"I Should Watch TV" playing
I used to think
that I should watch TV
that it was good for me
Wanted to know
what folks were thinking
To understand
the land I live in
And I would lose myself
And it would set me free
This is the place
where common people go
A global franchise
One department store
Yes, there were many
awkward moments
I had to do
some self-atonement
Well, if I opened up
Well, it would set me free
I know, I like
Behold and love
this giant
Big soul, big lips
That's me, and I am this
Everybody gets
a touched-up hairdo
Everybody's
in the passing lane
Had a reason
they can touch all channels
The weird things
that live in there
All right
I took a walk
Down to the park today
I wrote a song called
"Just Like You and Me"
I heard the jokes
from the sports reporters
The rival teams
when they faced each other
The more I lost myself
The more it set me free
How am I not your brother?
How are you not like me?
Everybody's
in the hotel lobby
I'm living in here
Yes, I am
I feel it moving
in my arms and fingers
Touch me and feel my pain
All right
It's good to lose
And it's good
to win sometimes
It's good to die
and it's good to be alive
Maybe someday
we can stand together
Not afraid of
what our eyes might see
Maybe someday
understand them better
The weird things
inside of me
About a year ago,
I invited a high school choir
in Detroit, Michigan,
to do an interpretation
of this next song.
The song's called
"Everybody's Coming to My House. "
Thank you.
And in my version,
and that's the version
you're gonna hear...
It... It kinda sounds like
the singer is not sure how he feels
about everybody
coming over to his house.
And you can sense, although
he never says it in the song,
you can sense that he's thinking,
"When are they gonna leave?"
In contrast, their version...
And this was kind of
a profound thing for me.
They didn't change a single lyric.
They didn't change the melody,
and yet their version has
a completely different meaning.
Their version seems to be
about welcome,
inviting everyone over, inclusion.
I kinda liked their version better,
and I didn't know how they did it.
Unfortunately, I am what I am.
Not sure how to take that applause.
We have people from many parts
of the world in this band.
Uh, I myself,
I'm a naturalized citizen.
I... My parents brought me over
from Scotland when I was little.
Yeah!
We have people from
Brazil, France, Colombia.
Most of us are immigrants, and
we couldn't do it without them.
"Everybody's Coming
to My House" playing
I wish I was a camera
I wish I was a postcard
I welcome you to my house
You didn't
have to go far
Well, there's a house
and a garden
There are plants and trees
Make a closer inspection
If you get, get down
on your knees
Now, everybody's
coming to my house
And I'm never
gonna be alone
Yeah, everybody's
coming to my house
And they're never
gonna go back home
I'm pointing
and describing
And I can be your guide
The skin is
just a road map
The view is very nice
Imagine looking
at a picture
Imagine driving in a car
Imagine rolling
down the window
Imagine opening
the door
Everybody's
coming to my house
I'm never gonna be alone
And they're never
gonna go back home
We're only tourists
in this life
Only tourists,
but the view is nice
And we're never gonna
go back home
No, we're never
gonna go back home
We're only tourists
in this life
Only tourists,
but the view is nice
And everybody's
coming to my house
And I'm never
gonna be alone
Yeah, everybody's
coming to my house
And they're never
gonna go back home
Everybody's
coming to my house
I'm never gonna be alone
And they're never
gonna go back home
Everybody's
coming to my house
I'm never gonna be alone
And they're never
gonna go back home
"Once in a Lifetime" playing
You may find yourself
living in a shotgun shack
in another part of the world
You may find yourself
Behind the wheel
of a large automobile
You may find yourself
in a beautiful house
With a beautiful wife
You may ask yourself
"Well, how did I get here?"
Letting the days go by
Let the water hold me down
Water flowing underground
Into the blue again
After the money's gone
Once in a lifetime
Water flowing underground
And you may ask yourself
"How do I work this?"
You may ask yourself
"Well, where is that
large automobile?"
You may tell yourself
"This is not
my beautiful house"
You may tell yourself
"This is not
my beautiful wife"
Letting the days go by
Let the water hold me down
Water flowing underground
Into the blue again
After the money's gone
Once in a lifetime
Water flowing underground
Same as it ever was
Water dissolving
and water removing
There is water
at the bottom of the ocean
Remove the water
Carry the water
From the bottom
of the ocean
Letting the days go by
Let the water hold me down
Water flowing underground
Into the blue again
Into the silent water
Under the rocks and stones
There is water underground
You may ask yourself
"What is that
beautiful house?"
You may ask yourself
"Well, where does
that highway lead to?"
You may ask yourself
"Am I right? Am I wrong?"
You may
say to yourself
"My God,
what have I done?"
Letting the days go by
Let the water hold me down
Water flowing underground
Into the blue again
Into the silent water
Under the rocks and stones
There is water underground
Letting the days go by
Let the water hold me down
Water flowing underground
Into the blue again
After the money's gone
Once in a lifetime
Water flowing underground
Same as it ever was
Time isn't holding us
Time isn't after us
Here comes the twister now
Here it comes,
here it comes
Letting the days go by
Once in a lifetime
Whoo!
Thank you!
"Glass, Concrete & Stone" playing
Now I'm waking
at the break of dawn
To send a little
money home
From here to the moon
Is rising like
a discotheque
And now my bags are down
and packed for traveling
Looking at happiness
Keeping my flavor fresh
Nobody knows, I guess,
how far I'll go
I know, so I'm leaving
at six o'clock
Meet in a parking lot
Harriet Hendershot
Sunglasses on
She waits by this
Glass
and concrete and stone
And it's just a house
Not a home
Skin that covers me
from head to toe
Except a couple
tiny holes
And openings
Where the city's
blowing in and out
And this is
what it's all about
Delightfully
Everything's possible
when you're an animal
Not inconceivable
how things can change
I know
So I'm putting on
aftershave
Nothing is out of place
Gonna be on my way
Try to pretend
It's not only
Glass
and concrete and stone
And it's just
a house
Not a home
And my head
Is 50 feet high
Let my body and soul
Be my guide
Whoo.
Thank you.
In 2016, just before the election,
I went to Charlotte, North Carolina,
to encourage people to register
if they weren't registered,
to encourage them to vote
if they were registered.
The election was in a couple of days.
We do something similar here.
We've partnered with an
organization called HeadCount.
They have a table in the lobby.
They'll register you instantly,
instantly, no matter
what state you're from.
We also did a thing called a pledge.
The pledge consists of a clipboard
and a piece of paper,
and I would go up to people and go,
"Are you gonna vote tomorrow?
"Will you sign this piece of paper
saying that you're
gonna vote tomorrow?"
This is not a legal document.
It was just a piece of paper,
but it's been shown that
when people put their name down,
it was like they'd made
a promise to themselves,
and it increased the odds
that they would actually turn up.
The turnout for that election
was the best it had been in decades.
Fifty-five percent of us
turned out to vote.
Okay.
Local elections are another matter.
Local elections,
the average turnout is 20%.
To give you a visual idea
of what 20% looks like,
here are 20%
of the people in this theater.
Here they are.
These are the ones
that vote in local elections.
The ones up top are waving and laughing
because, well, they just
decided your future
and the future of your children.
But you guys seem to be okay with that.
Here's another
little bit of information.
The average age of
the people who turn out
to vote in local elections,
that 20%, is 57 years of age.
- Whoo!
- Oh!
There we go.
Hey.
Congratulations.
Okay, yeah, but 57?
Climate change, right?
Kids...
you're fucked.
We gotta do better than 20%, really.
Local elections do make a difference.
We gotta do better than 55% too.
"Toe Jam" playing
I was asked
in New York City
"Do you like my clothes?"
I'm talking
to my tape recorder
Walking down the road
But on Friday night
I'm purified
Now my feet
don't touch the floor
When the rubber meets
the road in between my toes
Na, na, na, na
Na, na, na
Every day
is fucking perfect
It's a paradise
I watch my life
like it's a movie
I had to watch it twice
Now, a boy looks at a girl
And a girl looks
like a pony
She gallops all day long
In between my toes
And now every night
she's purified
She don't do
that dance no more
When the rubber meets
the road in between my toes
Na, na, na, na
Na, na, na
A member
of the Juju Nation
Down in New Orleans
You don't need
an application
If you move your feet
Explode if you poke it
Exposed on the floor
It grows if you soak it
It rolls out the door
Now it's summertime
every night
Now my feet
don't touch the floor
She don't do that dance
no more in between my toes
And now him and you,
you and I
I don't do
that dance no more
When the rubber meets
the road in between my toes
Na, na, na, na
Na, na, na
The lady
starts to sing
But she ain't
no disco dancer
She learned
to shake her thing
In between my toes
Explode if you poke it
Exposed on the floor
It grows if you soak it
It rolls out the door
Explode if you poke it
Exposed on the floor
- It grows if you soak it
- Na, na, na, na
- Na, na, na
- It rolls out the door
Whoo!
Thank you.
In 2018, we toured
a concert version of this show,
and we played a lot of places.
We played San Antonio twice.
So a friend of mine came to the show,
and we were talking backstage,
and he asked me,
"Are you really playing
all that music that we hear,
"or do you have, you know,
playback and tracks
and stuff like that?"
And I said, "I have nothing
against playback and tracks,
"but in this case everything you hear
"coming off the stage
is being played
by this incredible band. "
Whoo!
I figured other people were
maybe thinking the same thoughts
as my friend was thinking,
so I've continued to tell this story,
but it's not enough.
Journalists and reporters will...
they email, and would call
my office, and they go,
"I know what he says from the stage,
"but really?
Really?"
So I thought, "Okay, we have
to put this matter to rest. "
To do that, I'm gonna
introduce the band,
and as I do so, you're gonna hear
how the next song is put together
right in front of your ears.
From New York City, Daniel Freedman!
Toronto, Canada, Jacquelene Acevedo!
Red Bank, New Jersey, Tim Keiper!
Bahia, Brazil, Gustavo di Dalva!
Joacaba, Brazil, Mauro Refosco!
Montpellier, France, Stephane San Juan!
Chicago, Bobby Wooten!
Milwaukee, Angie Swan!
Palo Alto, Karl Mansfield!
Atlanta, Georgia, Tendayi Kuumba!
Paramus, New Jersey, Chris Giarmo!
Thank you.
"Born Under Punches" playing
All I want
is to breathe
Won't you
breathe with me?
Take a look
at these hands
The hands speak
The hand of
a government man
Well, I'm a tumbler
Born under punches
I'm so thin
All I want is to breathe
Breathe with me
Won't you breathe with me?
Find a little space
So we move in between
In between it
Keep one step
ahead of yourself
Don't you miss it
Some of you people
just about missed it
Last time to make plans
I'm a tumbler
I'm a government man
Never seen anything
like that before
What?
Falling bodies
tumble 'cross the floor
I said I'm a tumbler
When you get to
where you wanna be
Well, don't even mention it
When you get to
where you wanna be
Thank you, thank you
Take a look
at these hands
They were passing
in between us
Take a look
at these hands
You, uh, don't have
to mention it
No, thanks,
no, thanks
I'm a government man
Goes on, the heat goes on
And the heat goes on
Where the hand has been
- And the heat goes on
- I'm not a drowning man
And the heat goes on
- And the heat goes on
- And I'm not a burning building
- I'm a tumbler
- And the heat goes on
- Drowning cannot hurt a man
Where the hand has been
- And the heat goes on
- Fire cannot hurt a man
- Not the government man
- All I want is to breathe
- And the heat goes on, and the heat goes on
- Is to breathe
- And the heat goes on
And the heat goes on
- And the heat goes on, and the heat goes on
- Won't you breathe
With me?
- And the heat goes on
- Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba
- Find a little space
- And the heat goes on, and the heat goes on
- So we move in between
- And the heat goes on
- Keep one step ahead
Of yourself
"I Dance Like This" playing
In another dimension
Like the clothes
that you wear
A mighty, mighty battle
Sprouting illegal hair
A fitness consultant
In the negative zone
Wandering the city
Looking for a home
I dance like this
Because it feels
so damn good
If I could dance better
Well, you know that I would
I'm working
on my dancing
This is the best I can do
I'm tentatively shaking
You don't have to look
I can't say I'm sorry
Can't say
I'm ashamed
I can't think of tomorrow
When it seems so far away
We dance like this
Yeah, oh, yeah
Because it feels
so damn good
If we could dance better
Well, you know
that we would
We dance like this
Because it feels
so damn good
If we could dance better
Well, you know
that we would
"Bullet" playing
The bullet went into him
His skin did part in two
Skin that women had touched
But the bullet
went on through
The bullet went into him
It went its merry way
Like an old gray dog
On a fox's trail
The bullet went into him
His stomach
filled with food
Many fine meals
he tasted there
But the bullet
went on through
The bullet went into him
It went its merry way
Like an old gray dog
On a fox's trail
The bullet went into him
Through his heart
with thoughts of you
Where your kisses
he inhaled
The lies and the truth
The bullet went into him
It traveled
up into his head
Through thoughts
of love and hate
The living and the dead
The bullet
went into him
It went its merry way
Like an old gray dog
On a fox's trail
Thank you.
As you can see,
we don't have any cables or wires
attached to us in these shows,
attaching to gear or equipment
or any of those kinds of things.
We're completely untethered.
We can go wherever
we like on the stage.
It's very liberating.
When I began to think about the show,
I realized that,
well, what we humans like
looking at the most is,
yeah, other humans.
More than a bicycle,
more than a beautiful sunset,
and probably more than
a bag of potato chips.
So I thought
about the show, and I wondered,
"What if we could eliminate
everything from the stage
"except the stuff
we care about the most?
What would be left?"
Well, it would be us, us and you,
and that's what the show is.
"Every Day Is a Miracle" playing
The rose is pruned
To a perfect shape
Perfect for whom,
I wonder
The chicken thinks
in mysterious ways
But beauty
is not what we're after
Now, the chicken
imagines a heaven
Full of roosters
and plenty of corn
And God
is a very old rooster
And eggs are
like Jesus, his son
Every day is a miracle
Every day
is an unpaid bill
You've got to sing
for your supper
Love one another
A cockroach might eat
the "Mona Lisa"
The Pope don't mean
shit to a dog
And elephants
don't read newspapers
And the kiss
of a chicken is hot
The brain
of a chicken
And the dick
of a donkey
A pig in a blanket
And that's why
you want me
What does it feel like
To be your tongue
Moving around
in your mouth?
To feel free
in the forest of your love
A cockroach
In the cosmos
of your house
Every day
is a miracle
is an unpaid bill
You've got to sing
for your supper
Love one another
Every day is a miracle
Every day is
an unpaid bill
You've got to sing
for your supper
Love one another
"Blind" playing
Ha!
Signs
Signs are lost
Signs disappeared
Turn invisible
Got no sign
Somebody got busted
Got a face of stone
And a ghostwritten
biography
You know, well,
dogs start to rush in
And they're
looking for food
Dogs start to rush in
and they're looking at you
It was light
By five
Torn all apart
All in the name
of democracy
He's hurt!
He's dying
They claimed
he was a terrorist
Claimed to avert
a catastrophe
Oh, well, someone
should've told him
That the buck
stops here
Someone should have said
he was involved with thieves
And they're blind
- Blind
Blind, blind,
blind, blind, blind
- Blind
Blind, blind,
blind, blind, blind
No sense of harmony
No sense of time
Don't mention harmony
Say, "What is it?
What is it? What is it?"
Give a little shock
and he raises his hand
Somebody shouts out, says,
"What is it? What is it?
What is it?"
He was shot down
in the night
People ride by,
but his body's still alive
The girl in the window,
what has she done?
She looks down
at me and says
"I don't wanna die"
And they're blind
- Blind
Blind, blind,
blind, blind, blind
They're blind
- Blind
Blind, blind,
blind, blind, blind
Now, someone should have
told me where to go
Crawling all around
Looking for
foot, foot, footprints
Now tell me, what the hell
have we become?
Some dirty little bastards?
What the hell
is going on?
No sense of harmony
No sense of time
Don't mention harmony
Say, "What is it?
What is it? What is it?"
Give a little shock
and he raises his hand
Somebody
shouts out, says,
"What is it?
What is it? What is it?"
He was shot down
in the night
People ride by
But his body's still alive
Girl in the window,
what has she done?
She looks down
at me and says
"I don't wanna die"
And they're blind
- Blind
Blind, blind,
blind, blind, blind
- Yeah, they're blind
- Blind
- Yeah, blind
Blind, blind,
blind, blind, blind
Whoo
"Burning Down the House" playing
Ahh
Watch out
You might get
what you're after
Cool babies
Strange but not a stranger
I'm an ordinary guy
Burning down the house
Hold tight
Wait till the party's over
We're in for nasty weather
There has got to be a way
Burning down the house
Here's your ticket
Pack your bag
It's time
for jumping overboard
Transportation is here
Close enough
but not too far
Maybe you know
where you are
Fightin' fire with fire
Oh
All wet
Hey, you might
need a raincoat
Shakedown
Dreams walking
in broad daylight
Three hundred
and sixty-five degrees
Burning down the house
It was once upon a place
Sometimes
I listen to myself
Gonna come in first place
People on their way
to work said
"Baby, what did
you expect?"
Gonna burst into flame
Well, go ahead
Burning down the house
My house
is out of the ordinary
That's right
Don't wanna hurt nobody
Some things sure
can sweep me off my feet
Burning down the house
No visible means of support
And you have not
seen nothing yet
Everything's
stuck together
And I don't know
what you expect
Staring into the TV set
Fight fire with fire
Ohh
Burning down the house
Whoo!
Brr-rr.
Burning down the house
Thank you!
Thank you.
The next song was written by
the actress and singer Janelle Monáe.
She sang it at
the Women's March in Washington
a few years ago.
I was there.
I wrote to her a little bit afterwards
and asked what she would
think of a white man
of a certain age
singing this particular song.
The reason'll be clear in a minute.
She loved the idea.
She said the song is for everyone,
that it's for humanity.
It'll be obvious
the song is a protest song.
It's also a requiem,
a requiem for lives that have
been senselessly taken.
I also see the song
as being about possibility,
the possibility of change,
not just in
the imperfect world out there
but in myself, too.
I also need to change.
"Hell You Talmbout" playing
Hell you
Hell you talmbout?
- Eric Garner
- Say his name
- Trayvon Martin
- Botham Jean
- Say his name
Botham Jean
Hell you talmbout?
- Freddie Gray
- Say his name
- Atatiana Jefferson
- Say her name
- Sandra Bland
Sandra Bland
- Say her name
Hell you talmbout?
- Sean Bell
- Say his name
- Marielle Franco
- Say her name
- Emmett Till
- Say his name
Emmett Till
Hell you talmbout?
- Tommy Yancy
- Say his name
- Jordan Baker
- Amadou Diallo
- Say his name
Amadou Diallo
Hell you talmbout?
Thank you.
The writer James Baldwin said,
"I still believe
"that we can do with this country
something that has
not been done before. "
And this,
this from a man who has suffered
lifelong oppression and discrimination.
Despite all that's happened
and despite all that's still happening
I think there's still a possibility.
We're a work in progress.
We're not fixed.
Our brains can change.
Maybe those millions
of connections in our brains
that got pruned and eliminated
when we were babies
somehow get kind of reestablished,
only now instead of being in our heads,
they're between us and other people.
Who we are is thankfully not just here,
but it extends beyond ourselves
through the connections
between all of us.
"One Fine Day" playing
Saw the wandering eye
inside my heart
Shouts and battle cries
from every part
I can see those tears
Every one is true
When the door appears
I'll go right
Through
In a small, dark room
Where I will wait
Face to face
I find I contemplate
Even though
a man is made of clay
Everything can change
That one fine
One fine day
Then before my eyes
Is standing still
I beheld it there,
a city on a hill
I complete my tasks
one by one
I remove my masks
when I am done
Then a peace of mind
fell over me
In these troubled times
I still can see
We can use the stars
to guide the way
It is not that far
That one fine
One fine day
Hope
Oh, I have hope
I have hope
I have...
Hope
Whoo!
Thank you!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo!
Well, we know
where we're going
But we don't know
where we've been
And we know
what we're knowing
But we can't say
what we've seen
And we're not
little children
And we know
what we want
And the future is certain
Give us time to work it out
"Road to Nowhere" playing
We're on a road
to nowhere
Come on inside
Taking that ride
to nowhere
We'll take that ride
I'm feeling okay
this morning
And you know
We're on the road
to paradise
Here we go
We're on a road to nowhere
Come on inside
Taking that ride to nowhere
We'll take that ride
Maybe you wonder
where you are
I don't care
Here is where time
is on our side
Take you there
We're on a road to nowhere
Ha! Ha!
Ooh! Ooh!
There's a city in my mind
Come along
and take that ride
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
And it's very far away
But it's growing
day by day
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
Would you like
to come along?
You can help me
sing this song
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
Don't let them
tell you what to do
'Cause they'll make
a fool of you
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
There's a city in my mind
Come along
and take that ride
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
And it's very far away
But it's growing day by day
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
Would you like
to come along?
You can help me
sing this song
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
Don't let them
tell you what to do
They'll make
a fool of you
And it's all right
Baby, it's all right
We're on a road to nowhere
Yee-haw!
You better believe it, baby!
We're on a road to nowhere
Everybody, now, move 'em out!
Yep! Yep!
We're on a road to nowhere
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
Yee-haw!
We're on a road to nowhere
Hup, hup, hup, hup, hup, hup, hup!
Come on!
We're on a road to nowhere
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Yee-haw!
We're on a road to nowhere
You better believe it, baby!
Whoo!
Oh, my God. You okay?
Yeah.
Nice job with that balloon.
- Yeah. Right?
- Yeah.
- Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
That's the shit right there.
- That was, like...
- That's the shit right there.
That's it.
That's my boy!
That's how you do it!
That's how you...
Man.
- We need a hype man.
- "Now we're home free. "
That's right.
World Star.
Now we're home free.
- Thank you, David.
- Oh, thank you.
Yeah, that's what I'm talkin' about.
- That's it, right there.
- Whoo!
See you at rehearsal...
"Everybody's Coming
To My House" playing
I wish I was a camera
I wish I was a postcard
I welcome you to my house
You didn't have to go far
A house and a garden
There's plants and trees
Make a,
a closer inspection
If you get
down to your knees
Everybody's
coming to my house
And we're never
gonna be alone
And everybody's
Coming to my house
And we're never
gonna go back
Home
I'm pointing and describing
And I can be your guide
The skin
is just a road map
The view is very nice
Imagine looking
at a picture
Imagine driving in a car
Imagine rolling down
the window
Imagine opening the door
Everybody's
coming to my house
I'm never gonna be alone
And we're never
gonna go back home
We're only tourists
in this life
Only tourists
But the view
is nice
And we're never
gonna be alone
And we're never gonna
go back home
We're only tourists
in this life
Only tourists,
but the view
Is nice
And we're never
gonna be alone
gonna go back home
Everybody's
coming to my house
I'm never
gonna be alone
And we're never
gonna go back home
Everybody's
coming to my house
I'm never gonna
Be alone
And we're never
gonna go back home
Ay, ay, ay, ay. Ay, ay.
Ay, ay, ay, ay.